And then you're simply going to push down, into the pot.
You're going to want to get a little bit of water in that.
To reduce your friction. And you're going to push down, so you have about half an inch. On the bottom of the pot.
Now this is, this is something, why you just kind of, learn. Where that is. It's a trial and error process.
But once you get good at it, you'll just be able to push down.
And you'll know, pretty much where you are.
Now the next step is opening the form.
And we do that, with what's called the claw.
And you use your hand like this.
And you put it inside the pot.
And what I'm going to be doing, is pushing down.
And pulling towards me.
And this is going to open the form and create the base of the pot.
And so, here we go.
You just pull out and down.
You can see how that clay is just being forced into the position.
Now on a plant pot, the inside here needs to be pretty wide.
Because you want a nice base for the pot to sit on.
So part of opening the pot is forming your inside of your pot.
In this case, a plant pot.
And you know, I use this finger here.
As I'm gripping to create a nice edge on the inside.
And there we go.
We've now, we've entered and opened this form.
And the next part of what we're going to do, is pulling the clay up into the walls.
And then we're going to shape the pot.
And we're going to show you that, next.